hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and in this podcast I
share ways for you as a coach Mentor
trainer or if you're a content creator
how to monetize using subscriptions
memberships courses coaching programs
you name it if you want to sell digital
products online and have success doing
so I've been doing so for 21 years
successfully as the main focus of
basically everything that I do and I
want to pass on to you those lessons as
well now this I took a little bit of a
Hiatus off of doing the podcast for a
while and some of you might wonder the
reason why well let me
explain I've talked about my therapy
Journey for a while and how I've been
learning and growing in my own mental
health I had one of the biggest therapy
breakthroughs of my entire life but
here's what ended up happening was it
made it very difficult for me to
articulate on camera a lot of my
thoughts for a few months and this was
really hard for me I was like oh my
goodness I can do webinars I can do my
coaching calls but when it came to
creating content like this I felt like a
fish out of water and so what I want to
do for you here today is I actually want
to help you when it comes to creating
organic content and give you some ideas
for how to create content how to not run
out of ideas and also how to help your
brain when it comes with writer block
idea block sometimes we say writer block
but it's actually like you're blocked
with what you say or you're just not
sure or confident in what you're saying
now one thing that I do want to show you
is that we are actually also doubling
down on YouTube right now I just started
doing this a couple days ago we're going
to be having multiple videos per week I
got these kind of cool people call them
the think media style uh thumbnails that
are on here but what they are each one
is going to be an extensive training
that's on YouTube for free that's really
it's like like a like beyond the podcast
the podcast they're not going to be
super long episodes the YouTube channel
is actually going to be like many
courses that you can go through and you
can check out for free that will walk
you through one key aspect of building
your business online and particularly a
lot of people ask us about Facebook ads
and paid advertising and so I'm leaning
into that we're also going to be talking
about the best ways to make money online
we're going to be talking about how to
make sure that your business actually
works some of the functionalities of
running a business I've been helping
building running businesses been CEO of
businesses for years and so that's what
I'm going to be walking you through on
here and we're going to really be
leaning into using YouTube as a resource
for you in the coming months all right
so this podcast episode how do you get
to the place where you feel confident
when it comes to creating content right
we want to make sure that it's content
that helps make us look good and and
that's one of the biggest things that I
think that we're that we're really
concerned about is how do we appear like
somebody who's trustworthy some the
people actually want to listen to How do
we manage our reputation in a positive
way well if You' ever listened to me for
long enough you know that I I have a
LoveHate relationship with the term
manage your reputation I'm starting to
understand a bit more of what people
mean by it your character being a person
of your word being somebody who actually
does what they say they're going to do
having Integrity I'm all about those
things okay however you got to let go of
being concerned with what other people
think about you all the time and that
can take a while especially if you're
somebody who was traumatized has
cptsd or whatever diagnosis that maybe
people have and you're dealing with
these things internally because of stuff
that happened to you if I told you my
story which maybe another time we'll
share that with you I you know I don't
want to make this about my story I want
to make this about strategies for you
that can help but I experienced a lot of
things not not just in childhood but
even as an adult with friends with
family members with co-workers with
bosses with people at church that just
wired my brain to make it nearly
impossible to be the person that I was
born to be that I was called to be that
I wanted to be and some of you might be
listening to this right now saying no
Jeremiah that's just a crutch you're
just making excuses you are just lazy
you just you know you just need to get
over yourself well I get that and I
understand that because a lot of people
didn't experience the things that I've
experienced and I actually don't talk
about 95% of my traumatic experiences to
people okay and so again there are some
people that are out there not everybody
and I and I'm starting to see this more
and more not everybody but there are
some people where it's not that they
lack Integrity it's not that they lack
discipline I didn't lack
discipline it's not that they lack Drive
motivation desire or even the knowhow at
all it's literally that their brain is
wired to make it impossible for them to
take action and so that's why working
with a therapist really helped me as far
as that goes but there is one key lesson
that really helped me the most and I'm
just going to pass this on to you right
now so that you don't have to invest
weeks and weeks and months into therapy
how many you want to know what that is
right I'm sure all of you are like okay
wait Jeremiah there was one thing that
you learned from a couple years of
therapy that you could summarize it all
up into one thing here's what it is tell
you and if you start to apply this you
you will see changes in your life
however I got to I got to leave a little
warning here uh you you may see uh some
things may not go how you want them to
go but eventually they will start to
work out okay and and and I think you're
going to realize why that is when I tell
you what this secret
is it's learning to love
yourself the
way that other people who who made you
feel the safest in your entire life
loved
you and providing that safety for
yourself in every moment to where when I
wake up in the morning to where when I'm
in a tough situation to where when I'm
at my lowest
point the way that I did this was
there's there's different men and women
in my life that have been mentors that
I've looked up to that I've known
personally friends family members
and I would think about if I was sitting
down with them in my hardest moments in
time and I would do this during my
hardest moments in
time side note there's also a book by
Mel Robbins called the high F uh the
high five habit it kind of breaks down a
very similar concept of at your darkest
moments giving yourself a
high5 congratulating yourself showing
love to yourself
in those moments and you might be saying
Jeremiah what does self-love have to do
with creating content coming up with
ideas for Content I believe it has
everything to do with it because your
your self-esteem and what you believe
about yourself directly correlates to
your output when it comes to your
business because you are able to get out
of fight ORF flight you're able to hear
your inner voice better and you're able
to really show the World those deeper
parts of you that you've been hiding and
that my friends is what is effective
when it comes to creating content when
it comes to building a business online
is showing those vulnerable parts of you
that you have not been willing to show
other people for the longest
time for me there were parts of me that
I wasn't willing to show people I wasn't
willing to show up in a certain way I
was constantly in defense constantly
trying to defend my position trying to
prove to other people how smart I was
and and and people are like Jeremiah
like we we know you're smart you don't
need to prove it isn't that interesting
right like I've actually had to sort of
Dum myself down and actually get out of
the
smartness and get to where it's like
okay I can just be a normal human that
has fun and enjoys life and hangs out
like I do with my friends and family and
I and I don't got to try so hard and
when you get out of the trying so hard
moment you know there's actually a term
in video games I love video games as you
can tell there's a term in video game
playing called a try hard and it's sort
of a dig but if I think about it I've
always thought about it and I'm like you
know what that's so true is that when
you're trying so hard you're you're
you're operating out of like 5 to 10% of
your
capacity and this is what I see a lot of
people doing when it comes to their
business is they're just trying way too
hard to do all the
stuff to show up in a way that's going
to work for them their need for results
ends up demanding of them to try harder
to push harder and listen I know that
that works for some people and there are
times where you need to lean in where
you're going to have to do the hard
things where you're going to have to say
you know what suck it up buttercup do
the tough stuff
okay I'm not negating that I have to do
that all the time lit Lally sometimes
getting up in the morning is like that
it is okay but in the in the big picture
when you're struggling to have ideas
especially when you're creating content
for me I create content
mindlessly right now as I'm talking to
you right now and my very best webinars
sales copy campaigns in my business and
content are always done
mindlessly to where I'm not in my
thinking brain but I actually have what
a lot of people sometimes call mind
heart coherence and I'm doing a stream
of Consciousness type of a thing to
where I'm listening to my inner voice
and my
intuition and instincts all at the same
time and that is what's coming out on
camera okay and so when you can get to
that place where your inner voice your
intuition and then what you end up
typing and speaking don't have a lag
what's lag lag is where think of it this
way you how many of yall remember the
old days with computers or cell phones
or like you would open something up on
on the internet right dial up internet
and it would take a while for it to
load a lot of us that's what it's like
when it comes to our ideas we have a lag
time and a
hesitancy when it comes to implementing
our ideas
when in fact what I find and I would
challenge you to do and by the way gosh
I'm like literally kind of
teaching a a new way of a lot of the
stuff that Mel Robbins teaches people
Mel Robbins Is Amazing by the way how
many of y'all love Mel Robbins I think
that like just follow her content she's
awesome um not everything she teaches
but that you can't find anybody that you
agree with everything they say but she
really talks about
like like this is awesome the language
of lying how to catch a liar this is
great this is a good thing that you want
to learn right uh seven signs you have
high functioning depression and by the
way I guarantee you she talks about the
fact that like not everybody's lying you
know some people have trauma and things
like that Neuroscience how to end the
struggle and Stress and Anxiety I love
any of the stuff that she does with um J
shett I've you know jett's book uh think
like a monk so good but Mel Robbins
books really a big fan of these the high
five habit and as well she has this
concept called the 5c rule as well she
likes the number five a lot as you can
tell um the five second rule is this is
that when you have an idea or a thought
or an instinct to take action on it Go 5
4 3 2 1 and then take action on it
without thinking without
hesitating and this my friends is one of
the number one strategies that I can
tell you that listen I listen to Mel's
books I disagreed with like half of
everything she said I listened to Jay's
book think like a monk I disagreed with
80% of what he said in it and then what
ended up happening
was the 20% the 30% that I did agree
with I started applying and I started
doing and I started seeing the changes
in my life over the course of about 3
years ending my addiction with
punishment self-punishment self-loathing
disliking myself and actually learning
to like myself and if you also my faith
is in in God and in Jesus Christ but I
also believe that there are literally
also laws of the universe that God
created and that have that he has put in
order it's not that I'm worshiping the
Universe I worship the creator of the
universe but there's an order and a
structure to how everything is created
in creation and I think that one of
those things is the beauty of our minds
our brains and the fact that we don't
fully understand how our brains work
work but there are some things that
are truths that we can understand and
one of the truths is this is that when
you can learn to hear your inner voice
and you end up learning to calm your
nervous system
down to where you're not in fight ORF
flight to where you're not afraid all
the time to where you're
not worried what's going to happen
if and answering this question right
here this is this is a question that I
actually got from one of my mentors
is what am I trying to
avoid by not doing this thing by acting
this way by by speaking this way by
punishing Myself by disliking
Myself
by
overthinking all the stuff before I take
action by
hesitating by having that lag time
by being stuck some of us are actually
we find our identity in the
hesitation we find our identity in the
stuck place we find that we feel the
best being stuck and that if we became
unstuck it would challenge everything
that we believe about ourselves and what
we have thought to be true about the
world around
us this was the case for me is that I
saw myself as somebody who
was very
calculated very well put put together
and and I had to literally
create a Persona in my business when
with like how I have the design behind
me this is literally on Purpose By the
way I I mean a lot of people in business
they think that this is a sign of a lack
of self-discipline no this is literally
on purpose all of this is designed this
way to attract the right clients in my
business and to connect with the people
that I'm meant to connect
with I've been so curated in how I do
everything while creating a veneer a
very fragile
veneer that I don't really care that
much that I am unconcerned when the
truth is that I am one of the most
concerned people probably with how I
look with how I appear with how I sound
to people with how I'm received by
people because I know that I know that I
know that I can impact people and that I
know that there's a message inside of me
that has to come
out and I'm passionate about
it and if there are things that I can do
to make it more effective to do that I'm
going to do them but I also spent a lot
of time around millionaire and
multi-millionaire coaches and mentors
that had millions of followers people
who listened and hung on every word that
they had to say that were incredible
incredible leaders that I followed that
I am friends
with and I look at what do they do
differently than what I'm doing because
if they're at where I want to be there's
something that they know that I don't
know
yet and I began to look at that and I
would find they had
Charisma they were confident they were
out there they were bold they weren't
pass they weren't afraid of what
everybody thought about
them and a lot of us are like well yeah
they got there and then they had the
confidence can I challenge you in this
and this is something that I it's a hill
that I will stand
on you need to believe in yourself
first you need to believe that it's
possible for you to
succeed you need to start to
see yourself doing the thing before you
do it start visualizing it and really
own it in your being and anything that
comes in the way of that that's called a
block okay so we all have these blocks
and often times again this is where a
therapist can help I I would say not
everybody a therapist works for and I
get that and it's not that they need
that some people literally just need to
take action and find the blocks and find
the triggers and just be like okay this
is no longer going to stop me I'm going
to stop operating in this way I'm going
to stop reacting
you know my marriage got better when I
stopped reacting and defending myself
whenever my wife would point out
something that I could improve
on some of yall who are married are like
heck yeah you good on you for learning
that right wish I you know been been
married been been with my wife for 10
years uh been been married I think it
we're coming up on seven years
and wish I knew that on Year One
took me 10 years of
struggle to learn that you know and and
and and now there's a there's thriving
there's peace in our home it's beautiful
it's an amazing place it's a place where
where I'm excited for my kids to grow up
in the house I grew up in was not that
way and that's what I'm creating in my
life today and so can I tell you this
you can grow in skills that you're not
good
at you can learn new things that maybe
are not your Forte but I want you to
start to lean into your strengths and I
think that this is a powerful thing that
we all have inherent strengths and these
are the strengths that show up to the
people who really intimately see us the
people
who really support
us there's a lot of haters on social
media you're going to get haters just by
simply showing up and
existing you can't change that you can't
affect that you can't avoid that okay in
fact can I challenge you on this the
more haters you get the better you know
that you're on the right
track now eventually you'll refine your
message to where you get less and less
and less and I have found that to be the
case as well
but that also shows that you're in a
comfort zone if you're not getting
haters you're in a comfort zone and
sometimes it's good to be in a holding
pattern sometimes it's good to sustain
what you've
built but other times it's time to push
the envelope it's time to stretch
yourself it's time to do
something that you've not felt the most
confident
in and I would say for most people
content creation is that for most people
it's creating an offer it might be
launching a podcast putting a book out
there it might be creating a landing
page might be writing some sales copy it
might be growing your email list it
might just be creating a 60-second video
for
Instagram I want to challenge you on
this is
that what if you weren't
afraid what if you didn't let fear stop
you and then what if you learned a skill
set that I'm I'm going to teach you in
about 5 minutes right now and then we're
going to wrap this
up that's going to help you when you go
out there to create
content let me encourage you in what
this is so for me whenever I go out
there to create content now and I did
this in the beginning and then I stopped
doing it because there's so much crap
out there that people say you shouldn't
be doing this I literally had mentors in
my life telling me to not do this and
I'm
like it's literally the like the best
idea
ever is lean into what inspires
you when it comes to creating content I
want to challenge you on this is that
when it comes to anything really in your
business specifically often times we
separate
professional from
practical from what works and sometimes
it's like okay this works but I'm a
professional so I can't do that
thing and I have learned systematically
how to merge them all how to merge what
is effective in my life with what is
practical with what is
professional and so for me what I do is
I figure out what lights my soul on
fire makes me
excited stimulates me to the highest
degree and specifically it's not always
the same
thing for each moment in time
okay so for instance different things
will stimulate
me depending on what I'm wanting to go
do okay let me explain this in Practical
terms for me to show up as the best
father for my
son there are different things that will
inspire that in me and it takes me
usually a couple of minutes when I when
I got to transition from making content
like this for you guys to then you know
going to go play with my son they're
they're waking up right now there's a
little bit of a transition period for me
I I think there's like some Neuroscience
that that men have a bit of a longer
transition period than women I've been
learning to shorten that transition
period I I don't know if that's true or
not though it's it kind of sounds like a
weird thing that people just
say who knows um but neurologically I
have to transition from one St stage to
another and for me it takes me about 5
minutes it used to take me
weeks sometimes
months I would get stuck in a mental
Loop of a way of operating sometimes for
months or weeks and I would be living in
a memory or a feeling or something that
I was trying to avoid for the longest
time and I would be stuck there for
months in fact I just thought of
something right now where I've been
stuck for almost 6 months right now at
this moment in
time that I'm starting to gain Clarity
over the last couple of days on how to
get unstuck out of it's been one of my
things that I've been focusing on in the
background and I've learned that I can
transition
between different modalities and states
of mind more
quickly and here's what's funny I've
actually never like learned this part of
it from Tony Robbins or anything like
that a lot of people like I guess Tony
Robbins teaches a lot of this uh State
Management I've heard him talk about
that like on on Dr Oz or things like
that maybe I need to study more of his
stuff on this side of it but you know he
talks about literally if you just roll
your shoulders back for 3 minutes your
testosterone goes up and by the way
testosterone is a great hormone in your
body that creates
confidence it's it's a powerful thing
it's a good thing for you and so
literally if you're not feeling
confident just one thing you can do is
roll your shoulders
back hold your chest out and and hold
that and kind of stand there if you ever
notice like bodybuilder guys they walk
around like this it's because it
increases that
testosterone by doing that and and
literally the body is really just a
combination of
neurochemicals hormones and all of that
and did you know that media can trigger
your hormones differently I have proof
of this
and I realized the proof came from a
place that most people don't want to
talk about how many of y'all know that
there are certain content on the
internet that is adult
rated as well as certain books romance
novels things like that that have adult
rated
material and you feel a certain way if
you read or consume that content your
hormones are being triggered by the
content and I thought about this my
brain was like wait a sec
social media is doing this if I see a
baby versus a cat video versus a video
of a sports car versus a something about
a political candidate that I don't agree
with I feel a certain way and I realize
my hormones are
being manipulated even by the feed by
social media
right and then I realized that literally
everything in our world around us
creates stimulus that triggers different
internal chemical responses inside of
our
bodies you you don't need to understand
the science behind it I'm going to make
it real practical for you find stuff
that makes you feel the most excited the
most inspired and the
happiest and often times this is
something that I've noticed that a lot
of content creators coaches mentors and
trainers don't do they they confidently
say I don't cons consume video games I
don't watch movies I don't watch TV
shows and I challenge them to say you
know what you're going to become better
at the things that you're wanting to
become better at by possibly leaning
into different forms of media that can
trigger and Inspire different sort of
internal neurological and chemical
effects for you so here's how I do this
sometimes if I'm really really
struggling to create a certain piece of
content yesterday I had to make a
training on video editing absolutely
hated doing it so I started watching
content on my TV on YouTube I opened up
a game on my phone and started
doing strategic
distractions of stuff that I knew would
make me feel happy
temporarily and I and I've trained
myself that as soon as I feel that
dopamine hit and that happiness
from certain forms of media or things
like that that then immediately I turn
the media off and this is the part that
I think most people they don't
understand it's because they get sucked
into the media and they go deeper and
deeper and deeper and they get really
addicted to it and then they're watching
10 episodes of a TV show and then they
haven't made their content you don't
want to do
that sometimes I'll literally watch like
10 minutes of a TV show it might be a
documentary on soccer players and I'm
watching the coach lead the players and
I'm getting amped up and I'm getting
excited about them what they're doing or
I'll watch race car drivers or baseball
players Sports helps me a lot things
like that and then it starts triggering
ideas in my brain for the content that I
want to create as soon as I start
getting those ideas of how I want to
start the content I turn off the
entertainment and I immediately press
record on the content I literally did
that before this podcast
episode and what that does is it gets me
into that brain heart coherence state to
where I'm unstuck and I'm excited to
take action and I'm no longer afraid or
worried to do the things that I've been
avoiding I even started doing this in my
in my uh daily life to make me more
productive when it comes to things like
washing the dishes or cleaning things in
my house I noticed that certain types of
music would trigger me into being more
likely to want to clean my house and
then I realized that some of that music
was actually related to some of the
favorite genres of music that I had when
I was younger and so I just want to
challenge you in this that sometimes
becoming more Whimsical becoming more
playful learning how to tap into having
more fun is actually the key to you
feeling more confident showing up as
your best
self and not being so stuck or hesitant
all the time you might hesitate to do
what I just said in this video to
consume some form of media or content
one of the probably one of the safest
ways that we all use is scrolling social
media you know I we talk about how
that's a dangerous thing and it's
addictive and it's something that we
want to be careful of but you can
actually strategically use it if you're
feeling
anxious about making content you can
scroll social media a little bit I'll do
it for 5 minutes and then as soon as I'm
no longer feeling anxious I turn it
off I put the phone down and then I go
do the thing that I've been
procrastinating on and if I still can't
do the thing I start asking myself in my
brain okay what do I really want to do
right
now you know I saw I saw a post that
says that you know a a writer who has
writer block always comes up with
distractions and listen distraction is
one of the number one things that
actually stops us from succeeding I'm
not talking about actually distracting
yourself with stuff what I'm talking
about is using basically they talk they
talk about this when it comes to like
drugs and stuff micro doing distraction
that's so weird but like it's actually
what it is we're micro consuming
distractions in order to trigger just
enough of the
neurological and chemistry inside of our
bodies to then drive ourselves and pivot
ourselves to go in a Direction that's
going to help us do the things that are
going to help
us and so this is something I've been
using I've been doing it has made me way
more more effective in my marriage has
it's made me a better husband it's made
me more effective in my home it's made
me more organized it's made me much
better as a coach as a mentor as
somebody who I now feel super confident
in my time management I'm literally
getting more done in less time by
learning to just enjoy life more to not
be so stuck on trying to do everything
perfect to not hesitating before I take
action and then utilizing different
forms of media whether it be fiction
sometimes it's non-fiction there's an
incredible non-fiction book that I'm
reading right now uh by an author her
name is uh Michelle Ashman right here
what would you do if you weren't afraid
really really great book that I'm
reading right now discover a life filled
with purpose and joy through the secrets
of Jewish wisdom and by the way some of
what I just shared here today I even
learned from that book this week which
is amazing literally lessons that I
learned reading that book inspire me
stuff that I knew inside of me that I'm
feeling more and more confident in
sharing with people because it was
validated by hearing another leader that
I respected and wanted to listen to
share it okay so some of you you've not
listened to any Audi books you've not
consumed any content listen if you don't
want to consume entertainment start
where I
started listen to podcasts listen to
this podcast even the previous episodes
of the podcast are absolutely incredible
they will inspire you they will give you
ideas and Clarity and
focus this podcast right here could
literally be the Catalyst for you to go
to the next level in your business to
help inspire you because then you get to
be around my energy and you get to
attach to this energy and then what ends
up happening is your energy starts
mirroring this the mirror neurons in
your brain start firing and then you
start showing up in that way when you
start creating content as well and so my
goal is this is I want you to get to
where you can create content mindlessly
to where you're not overthinking the
process of making content to where you
feel
inspired to say things you're not
hesitant you're willing to even say the
crazy things you're even willing to say
stuff that maybe you don't have the most
evidence or proof for can I tell you
that and you're willing to say Hey
listen I'm not an expert in this uh
these are my experiences it's one of the
best ways that I find that if I don't
have like clerical evidence for
something right I I said it a few times
in this podcast I'm not an expert in a
in a lot of the Neuroscience stuff like
this but there's a few things that I
know that are true and I was able to
just share them from the perspective of
what I've learned in my experiences with
you and so we don't need to be afraid
anymore we don't need to operate out of
fear and worry and shame and guilt and
when you can get out of that shame fear
worry and guilt cycle you become more
effective and this is what ends up
happening we're trying to maintain
our sense of safety all the time because
whenever we felt shamed or guilty or
afraid we felt unsafe and then often
times when it comes to building our
business growing our business creating
the content that we want to create we
end up operating in this cycle of Shame
guilt fear that then wires us to where
we're trying to control that we're
trying to control the perceptions of us
we're trying to manage and maintain
other people's opinions of us we're
trying to manage our reputation way too
closely way too tightly right like I
said character is important Integrity is
important being a person that does the
things that they say they're going to do
is important you need to start doing
those
things
absolutely but you also need to do the
stuff that you've been avoiding that
you've been procrastinating and I can
tell you right now like so confidently
if you can get
this start loving yourself the way that
the most protective and safe person in
your life showed love to you and
protection to you and wrap your arms
around yourself in a
hug anytime you feel
unsafe Watch What Happens it'll impact
you in a positive way and you will see
incredible positive changes in your life
all right everybody this has been the
grow Your Life podcast if this has
helped you share it with somebody we got
an incredible episode coming up here uh
that I did with one of my clients as
well as an incredible uh man I'm not g
to um blow it all for you right now but
what it is we had an incredible
conversation that we recorded this past
week with uh it was a it was a three-way
conversation that we had online all
about deeper ways to implement a lot of
what I talked about here
today it's like it's like step two to
what I just talked about and I think
you're going to really like it next week
so plug in stay plugged in follow me on
YouTube watch the content and start
implementing and building your business
I believe you can do it I I don't just
say that I know that if you start
applying this stuff you're going to see
changes in your life all right talk soon
everybody have a good one
[Music]
[Applause]